Bryan Stevens

Colorado Springs, Colorado

b.stevens.bit@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/bryan-stevens314

I am a highly skilled and motivated professional with over 3 years of experience in the tech industry. I have a strong background in software development and project management, and I am always looking for new challenges and opportunities to grow and learn.

Experience

VuSpex - Software Engineer

June 2021 – Present

- Adeptly implemented the Scrum methodology, ensuring successful delivery of projects
- Leveraged software engineering knowledge to drive development resulting in lower customer support cases.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to deliver high-quality, user-friendly solutions on time.

VuSpex - Junior Software Developer

May 2020 – June 2021

- Effectively translated client requirements into intuitive solutions demonstrating strong analytical skills.
- Used innovative approaches to quickly and efficiently troubleshoot a range of technical issues.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to deliver high-quality, user-friendly solutions on time.

StreamGuys - Junior Software Developer

September 2019 – May 2020

- Efficiently translated complex requirements into solutions that met specific needs and improved workflows.
- Quickly identified and resolved technical issues using creative problem-solving skills to find effective solutions.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to deliver high-quality, user-friendly solutions on time.

Projects

- (2021) VuSpex GO: React Native OpenTok Geolocation Services: Developed as a cross-platform solution to replace VuSpex's existing iOS and Android mobile apps, utilizing a single code base. This innovative solution leverages webRTC and GPS technologies to facilitate virtual inspections, generate field reports, and schedule inspections with ease, resulting in a significant reduction of customer support cases and streamlining processes for contractors, field agents, and permit applicants.
- (2020) ELevel+: React Native Redux React Native Bluetooth LE: As part of a contract team of three, I played a key role in the development of an app that seamlessly integrates with AccuAir's Bluetooth module. The app effectively receives, displays, and updates real-time height and position indicators, as well as providing diagnostic feedback to enhance user experience. A key feature of the app is its ability to perform chunked OTA updates, enabling the app to upgrade the four components of AccuAir's firmware stack with ease.
- (2016) Bitcoin Faucet: Objective-C: The app leveraged multiple advertising networks to mediate and display advertisements to users. To incentivize usage, small amounts of Bitcoin were rewarded to users for viewing advertisements, creating a unique user engagement experience. Over a period of several months, the app achieved significant success, with over 4.2K total downloads and over 230,000 user sessions recorded.

Education

Fullstack Academy of Code

October 2018 – February 2019

- Highly selective software engineering bootcamp with a 9% acceptance rate.
- Acquired advanced skills and knowledge in software engineering.
- Acquired in-depth knowledge of Object-Oriented Design, asynchronous programming, and software design
- Honed collaboration and communication skills through extensive pair-programming practice.

Technical Skills

Advanced: React, Javascript, Typescript, React Native, Swift, Objective-C, Kotlin, Java, Git, SQL, PHP Knowledgeable: AWS, GraphQL, NoSQL, C#, Angular, Jest